<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Kamron Mirsamatov</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Kamron Mirsamatov</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 21:48:54 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Reinventing the &#34;wheel&#34; to learn programming</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/howilearnprogramming/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 21:47:54 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/howilearnprogramming/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Now we are at a point where new people in the IT industry start learning about
programming straight ahead from programmming languages. Programming is not only
about the syntax it is about thinking like an engineer to
come up with sophisticated solutions. Therefore, I focused on learning
computer science fundamental topics such as computer architecture, compilers,
operating systems, algorithms and data structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might ask, why would you waste your time reinventing the wheel? Well, because
if you don&amp;rsquo;t know these basics and how the program works inside out, you are not
a real engineer, you are just another user with bunch of external libraries and
frameworks by connecting them with each other and calling it a final product. The reason in my opinion why newbies may struggle
to feel like true developers when faced with a job is that requirements that include many
abstract frameworks and tools, rather than allowing for more hands-on coding
experience. A lot of beginners these days (including myself) learn popular
frameworks that are used in the field and then apply for jobs without having an
understanding of the underlying mechanisms involved. The problem with those &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Soydev&#34;&gt;soydevs&lt;/a&gt; when they have to move to another project, it is gonna take them a lot more time to get
used to because they lack foundational computer science skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now we are at a point where new people in the IT industry start learning about
programming straight ahead from programmming languages. Programming is not only
about the syntax it is about thinking like an engineer to
come up with sophisticated solutions. Therefore, I focused on learning
computer science fundamental topics such as computer architecture, compilers,
operating systems, algorithms and data structures.</p>
<p>You might ask, why would you waste your time reinventing the wheel? Well, because
if you don&rsquo;t know these basics and how the program works inside out, you are not
a real engineer, you are just another user with bunch of external libraries and
frameworks by connecting them with each other and calling it a final product. The reason in my opinion why newbies may struggle
to feel like true developers when faced with a job is that requirements that include many
abstract frameworks and tools, rather than allowing for more hands-on coding
experience. A lot of beginners these days (including myself) learn popular
frameworks that are used in the field and then apply for jobs without having an
understanding of the underlying mechanisms involved. The problem with those <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=Soydev">soydevs</a> when they have to move to another project, it is gonna take them a lot more time to get
used to because they lack foundational computer science skills.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s also why, even in high ranked universities like MIT and Harvard, there are still classes
of algorithms and data structures, low-level programming languages like C and
so on to give students the understanding of how a technology works. Once you
know these little details everything else makes sense and becomes possible.
Do not fall for the hype of the industry, learn the fudamentals and this will get you far.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Information overload</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/information/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 18:41:27 +0200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/information/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This little essay is in the first place a reminder for my future self to avoid consuming content mindlessly and focus on things in life that &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are bombarded with an infinite flow of information 24/7 on the internet and we consume the content without realizing its consequences. We consume content but we do not process it afterwards. And social media apps on our phones made this process very easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This little essay is in the first place a reminder for my future self to avoid consuming content mindlessly and focus on things in life that <em>actually</em> matter.</p>
<p>We are bombarded with an infinite flow of information 24/7 on the internet and we consume the content without realizing its consequences. We consume content but we do not process it afterwards. And social media apps on our phones made this process very easy.</p>
<p>We should not take every piece of information as a fact but instead try to rationalize it and then see if we can somehow implement that in our lives in the right way. One great book, movie or talk can change how we think. In order not to fall for a random person&rsquo;s claims on the internet, we should know the reason why we are doing certain things, we can use it as a compass and optimize our lives around it.</p>
<p>When it comes to learning any subject, there are some good and free resources but we do not value what comes for free. Many people value only that learning material for which they had to pay. On top of that, we seek different methods to be &ldquo;productive&rdquo; but what really increases our focus is being offline. This process is also called &ldquo;dopamine detox&rdquo;. Of course, in the beginning, there is going to be a feeling of boredom as we were consuming all generated content 24/7 and that messed with our neurotransmitters in the brain. So, how do we know what is important and what is not? Well, by just thinking about death, we will immediately realize what is truly important because death gives meaning to life.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Studying cybersecurity</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cybersecurity/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 18:41:27 +0200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cybersecurity/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity careers are one of the fastest-growing and in-demand fields of IT
nowadays. I had no idea about this field before, even if I was interested in
IT. I only came across it when I was watching a video about IT
certifications that help people to get an IT job. And in fact, exams to get
these certifications are not very expensive, have up-to-date topics, and get
people job faster than standard universities in most cases. After some google
search, I found a website called tryhackme, hackthebox and so on. And when I
started to study on these websites, I discovered for myself a whole new field of
cybersecurity. Then I watched videos of professionals in this field and their
views. After some hands-on experience on tryhackme.com, I got really into that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cybersecurity careers are one of the fastest-growing and in-demand fields of IT
nowadays. I had no idea about this field before, even if I was interested in
IT. I only came across it when I was watching a video about IT
certifications that help people to get an IT job. And in fact, exams to get
these certifications are not very expensive, have up-to-date topics, and get
people job faster than standard universities in most cases. After some google
search, I found a website called tryhackme, hackthebox and so on. And when I
started to study on these websites, I discovered for myself a whole new field of
cybersecurity. Then I watched videos of professionals in this field and their
views. After some hands-on experience on tryhackme.com, I got really into that.</p>
<p>However, cybersecurity is a very broad field and after some learning, it is important to find your niche. Here are some careers in this field:</p>
<ul>
<li>Red teamer</li>
<li>Blue teamer</li>
<li>Threat hunter</li>
<li>Malware analyst</li>
<li>Application pentester</li>
<li>Security architect and so on</li>
</ul>
<p>There are different roadmaps to achieve what you want. For instance, by having certifications such as security+, OSCP, eJPT and so on, you will have a better chance to get a job in this field. Personally, I have been learning penetration testing by solving capture the flags (CTF), and going through portswigger&rsquo;s web academy to learn more about web vulnerabilities.</p>
<h3 id="edit-160922">Edit 16.09.22</h3>
<p>I realized that it is hard to get an entry-level job as a cybersecurity
specialist. Yes, it is true that this field is still in-demand, but currently,
most companies do not care about securing their infrastructure as much as
building and maintaining it. Also, it became clear to me that without actually having a view
of how the system is built from inside, it is difficult to find a
vulnerability. And people who are new to the field become <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=script%20kiddies">Script kiddies</a> without good knowledge of basics of computing. In most cases, by using latest
versions of frameworks and writing more or less secure code, it is not
difficult to build a secure system. Up until now, I have been reading and practicing the
foundations of computer science and Golang.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Linux vs Windows</title>
            <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux_and_windows/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 19:18:54 +0200</pubDate>
            
            <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux_and_windows/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays almost everyone uses Windows or Mac operating system, and only a few choose Linux as their daily driver. It is mostly because Linux is not as popular as Windows or Mac. After all, there is no big corporation behind it, or there are stereotypes such as &lt;em&gt;Linux is only for programmers and it is difficult to use one&lt;/em&gt;. I am not going to write about Linux elitism or the difference between free and open-source, and proprietary software. Here I just simply compare Linux and Windows. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s look at some advantages of using Linux over Windows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Nowadays almost everyone uses Windows or Mac operating system, and only a few choose Linux as their daily driver. It is mostly because Linux is not as popular as Windows or Mac. After all, there is no big corporation behind it, or there are stereotypes such as <em>Linux is only for programmers and it is difficult to use one</em>. I am not going to write about Linux elitism or the difference between free and open-source, and proprietary software. Here I just simply compare Linux and Windows. Now, let&rsquo;s look at some advantages of using Linux over Windows.</p>
<ul>
<li>It is free and open-source (Windows is proprietary, which means your data is not 100% secure)</li>
<li>More secure (no antiviruses needed)</li>
<li>Lightweight (it can run perfectly on very old computers)</li>
<li>No forcing updates (Microsoft forces to update)</li>
<li>Full of control (you can customize, delete and do whatever you want with your OS)</li>
<li>Many distributions (you can choose the distribution that suits your needs)</li>
</ul>
<p>However, if you mainly use Adobe software, play games, and use software that can run only in Windows, it would be not a good idea to switch to Linux. However, there are many free and open-source alternatives for Linux as well.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
